UK / French / Lebanese nationalities Currently based in London, United Kingdom thomas@seropian.io https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tseropian

Tech Lead / Lead Software Engineer

Profile

I am a software engineer with 15 years of experience building tech solutions across several industries with a strong entrepreneurial focus. I am equally comfortable with hands-on delivery (i.e. writing code) and managing engineering teams (i.e. helping other developers write code). I help organisations embrace new technologies to solve challenging real-world problems and launch successful products that customers love.

Work experience

Tech Advisor / interim CTO (part-time) for an early-stage startup

Emani.io, London, United Kingdom - November 2020 to March 2021 (emani.io)

Hiring an engineering team, building product road map, tech strategy and delivering the core product.

→ <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Serverless (Lambda) TypeScript, Node.js, React, DynamoDB, GraphQL.

Senior Backend Engineer (contract based) for a US-based life sciences startup

ApprenticeFS, London, United Kingdom - Sept. to Dec. 2021 (apprentice.io)

Building new features for an intelligent pharmaceutical manufacturing execution system SaaS platform.

→ <u>Technology:</u> TypeScript, Node.js, Docker, Angular12, MongoDB, NX, AWS, Elasticsearch.

Lead Software Engineer (contract based) for a global publishing house

Conde Nast, London, United Kingdom – Mar. to Sept. 2021 (condenast.com)

Building and Improving a content migration tool for Conde Nast's in-house engineering teams.

Working for a software consultancy (YLD) on improving a set of APIs and tools automating content migration for 50 publications to a new tech stack. Writing code and delivering new features. Code reviews.

→ <u>Technology:</u> Node.js, TypeScript, GraphQL, Express, React, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, CircleCl, OAuth

Senior Backend Engineer (contract based) for a content marketing agency

Progressive Content, London, United Kingdom – Sept. 2020 to Feb. 2021 (<u>progressivecontent.com</u>)

Building a microservices backend for a UK-based banking client's content marketing CMS.

→ <u>Technology:</u> Serverless (Lambda), TypeScript, GraphQL, Node.js, Docker, Jenkins, AWS, Elasticsearch.

Mentor, since 2017

→ Mentoring for the tech lead curriculum for the primary french online education platform Open Classrooms

Lead Backend Engineer (contract based) for a software consultancy

AND Digital, London, United Kingdom - July 2019 to April 2020 (www.and.digital)

Leading a development team part of a cloud transformation project for a UK insurance client.

Managing a team of 4 developers. Writing code for replatforming an end-user web application. Integrating with 3rd party back-office services (both REST and SOAP). Refining user stories. Code reviews. Agile (SCRUM) delivery.

→ <u>Technology:</u> Serverless, TypeScript, Express, Node.js, React, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure, REST, SOAP.

Head of Engineering for a health-tech startup

Skin Analytics, London, United Kingdom – October 2017 to May 2019 (www.skin-analytics.com)

→ Responsible for clients, internal and commercial applications and infrastructures

Managing applications, cloud infrastructure and releases. Defining roadmaps and priorities and scoping new requirements. Writing code. Hiring and leading technical team (8 members between London and Poland). Day to day management, code reviews and testing. Delivered a Software as a Medical Device commercial API.

→ <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, Serverless (Lambda), TypeScript, React, MySQL, MongoDB, Docker, Ansible.

Technical Lead for an international online media publishing group

Jamie Oliver, London, United Kingdom – February to September 2017 (www.jamieoliver.com) Lead a migration from a legacy SOAP CRM to a microservices architecture. Managing contractors.

→ <u>Technology:</u> AWS, Node.js, TypeScript, PHP (Laravel), RESTful APIs, Redis, Solr, Vue.js, WordPress, Varnish.

Team Leader / Technology Manager for an international NGO

Internews London, United Kingdom – April 2015 to December 2016 (www.internews.org)

- → Leading the design, development, and delivery of innovation and technology components

 Working with a multidisciplinary team supporting local startups among the most repressive regimes. Leading on delivering news publishing apps. Managing activities' budgets. Speaking at conferences and events.
- → Managing technology team and resources across multiple projects (8 countries)

 Overseeing the recruitment and day-to-day managing a team of 5 technologists. Ensuring planning, setting priorities, agreeing on detailed work plans, budgets, and schedules. Coaching and mentoring team members. Agile delivery. Responsible for technical architecture and roadmap. Focus on scalability & security.
- → <u>Technology:</u> Node.js, PHP (Laravel), WordPress, Drupal (7/8), Ansible, Nginx, OpenVPN, encryption.

Web Application Engineer for an international NGO

Internews Paris, France / London, United Kingdom - Mar. 2009 to Mar. 2015 (www.internews.org)

- → Online freedom of expression, support of local media, digital security

 Designing, developing & supporting multilingual web applications, custom modules. Integration with social network (Twitter, Facebook) APIs. Writing documentation for users. Deployment and monitoring of secure hosting & video platforms. Facilitating training & trainers: website building and digital security (West Africa, MENA).
- → <u>Technology</u>: Drupal, WordPress, PHP (OOP, MVC), MySQL, Solr, AWS, Vagrant, Nginx, Linux administration

Software Engineer for a social networking service designed for a family use **Hellotipi.com** Paris, France – February 2008 to January 2009 (<u>www.hellotipi.com</u>)

→ <u>Technology</u>: MySQL, PHP5 (OOP, MVC), XML, Jquery, Ffmpeg, Debian, Linux administration

ICT Projects Manager for a local NGO in Armenia

Fondation KASA Yerevan, Armenia - March 2006 to September 2007 (www.kasa.am)

Coordinated Computer training in youth training centres. Developed activities in the two major cities. Managed the recruitment of the local team. Provided technical support for training & social programs.

Junior Software Engineer for e-training IT projects for an international training centre **Valeo Thermal Systems** Paris, France – March 2005 to February 2006 (www.valeo.com) Designed & implemented tools for course support creation (virtual classes, e-learning modules).

Education

MSc in Computer Sciences and Innovation

Ecole Supérieure d'Informatique, Electronique, Automatique Paris, France

5 years engineering school in information technologies & electronics (<u>www.esiea.fr</u>)

 \rightarrow Graduated with first class honours.

Foreign languages

French: Mother tongue English: Fluent Spanish: Basic level Arabic: Beginner

Hobbies

Collecting records (LPs), mostly nerdy noisy music. <u>Photography</u> (film and digital). Part of the media team of a <u>non-league fan-owned football club</u> in East London.